（ロゼ）あんたら…
You bastards...
You would harm your own princess?!
（ロゼ）自分とこの姫様を！
何をしている！
早く捕らえぬかあっ！
What are you doing?! Hurry up and capture her!
Sorry...
（ロゼ）ごめん…
Wh-What?!
あ… うぐっ
All right, listen up.
ほら お前ら
手に持ってるもの 離しな
Drop your weapons.
じゃないと あんたらの親分
やっちゃうよ
Otherwise, your leader is a goner.
こちとら本気で怒ってんだ
I'm pissed.
Really, really pissed.
超 怒ってるって…
Did you hear me?!
言ってんだろ！
Urgent message!
（兵士１）伝令！
伝令ー！
You're ordered to cease fighting!
（兵士２）停戦命令！
（サイモン）ウッフフフ…
もう おしまいなのか
It's over already?
つまらぬ
How boring.
We need more killing, more hatred.
（サイモン）
もっともっと 殺し合って―
憎しみ合ってもらわないと
ねぇ 我が主(あるじ)よ
Isn't that right, my lord?
That's...
（スレイ）あれは…
（エドナ）この領域
今まで感じたどれよりも…
This domain is worse than anything we've felt before.
（ミクリオ）
冗談じゃない これほどの穢(けが)れ…
This can't be right. This malevolence...
（ライラ）まさか…
Could it be?
スレイさん
Sorey...
これほどの邪悪な領域を持つ者は
かの者しか考えられませんわ
I can only think of one hellion that can have such a malevolent domain.
（スレイ）
あいつが“災禍の顕主(けんしゅ)”！
So he's the Lord of Calamity?
あいつ 人間の憑魔(ひょうま)だ
A human hellion.
（ミクリオ）これが人間！？
That's a human?!
（スレイ）
なのに人間の姿が見えない
But I can't see the human form.
Why?
どうして…
あ… スレイ！
Sorey!
Let us go, Edna.
行きましょう エドナさん
スレイをここで
死なせるわけには いかないわね
I suppose we can't let Sorey die here.
（ライラ）はい
（ミクリオ）こんなやつを
浄化なんて できるのか？
Is it even possible to purify this guy?
ミクリオ
Mikleo...
Over here!
こっちだ
Sorey!
（ミクリオ）スレイ！
（スレイ）うっく…
As the Shepherd, it's my duty to purify you...
導師としてお前を浄化する
災禍の顕主よ！
Lord of Calamity!
（ヘルダルフ）導師…
Shepherd...
How dare you speak to my lord?
貴様 我が主に向かって
（ヘルダルフ）フッフッフッフ…
Show me what you can do.
見せてみよ お前という器を
くうっ…
でやあああっ
わしを浄化しようなどと―
You wish to purify me?
生意気な
Such insolence!
Sorey!
スレイ！
新たな導師が現れていたとはな
I was not aware that a new Shepherd had appeared.
恐ろしいか
Are you afraid?
死の予感
The premonition of death is sweet, is it not?
甘美であろう
Lailah!
（スレイ）ライラ
フォエス＝メイマ！
Fethmus Mioma!
でやぁっ！
（ヘルダルフ）ふんっ！
てやっ
ぬあっ
（スレイ）どあっ
Shepherd...
（ヘルダルフ）導師よ
ぬおぉっ
It is imperceptible to ordinary humans.
（ヘルダルフ）人の目に
見えぬことを いいことに―
あらゆるところに穢れが
侵食しているのが見えるだろう
But you can see how the malevolence has permeated everywhere, can't you?
災禍の顕主
Lord of Calamity...
（ライラ）スレイさん！
今の私たちのかなう相手では…
Sorey, we are no match for him right now!
（ヘルダルフ）フッフフフ…
（ライラ）はっ！
皆の者 わしのもとに来るがよい！
All of you, come to me!
The malevolence...
（スレイ）穢れが…
is gathering!
（ミクリオ）集まっていく
How is this possible?
（ライラ）こんなこと…
災禍の顕主
あなたは これほどまでに…
Lord of Calamity, you would go this far?
（ヘルダルフ）導師よ
Shepherd...
Show me that you can survive this onslaught of hellions.
この憑魔たちの穢れから
生き延びてみせよ
Go!
行け！
ぐうう うっ…
うおっ ぬうっ…
Can you endure it?
耐えられるか
This is human malevolence. Behold its power.
これが人間の穢れ 強さだ
ぐうぅ おおおおぉっ
でやっ
（ヘルダルフ）人間のために
浄化しているお前を―
You purify for the sake of humans...
But you are assaulted by malevolence from man.
攻撃しているのは
人間から生まれた穢れ
Unfair, isn't it?
まさに理不尽
愉快よのお…
I delight in the irony.
ハァ ハァ ハァ…
I believe...
（スレイ）俺は信じる
I will purify the world one day!
いつしか
世界を浄化しきれるって！
人間が在るかぎり
この地の穢れは無尽蔵
As long as humans exist, there will always be malevolence.
It will never end.
終わりはないぞ
I believe!
俺は信じる！
Some day...
いつか 人と天族が
一緒に暮らせる世界が来るって！
Humans and seraphim will live together in harmony!
（マルトラン）アリーシャ！
Alisha!
アリーシャ！
Princess, hang on!
（イアン）姫様 しっかり！
（マルトラン）
くっ… 血が止まらない
I can't stop the bleeding.
Where are the medics?!
救護班は まだか！
They should be on their way already.
（シレル）
今 呼びに行かせていますが…
様子を見てきます
I'll go check.
（マルトラン）アリーシャ！
Alisha!
（イアン）姫様？
Princess!
せ… 先生…
L-Lady Maltran...
How do you feel, Alisha?
大丈夫か アリーシャ
（アリーシャ）先生…
Lady Maltran...
Has the fighting stopped?
戦いは止まりましたか…
Yes, it stopped. It's okay now.
（マルトラン）ああ 止まった
もう大丈夫だ
はっ…
（イアン）姫様！
Princess...
（ロゼ）死ぬな 姫様
Don't die, Princess.
I'll bring Sorey as fast as I can.
今 スレイを連れてくる
導師なら…
The Shepherd...
導師なら…！
He'll be able to...
死ぬな 姫様！
Don't die, Princess!
Everyone's alive.
（ルナール）みんな生きてやがる
（ルナール）姫様が死んじまったら
次は何をして遊ぶかなぁ
If the princess dies, what will I toy with next?
しかし この穢れは
俺でも強すぎてしんどい！
But seriously, this malevolence is too thick even for me.
（兵士１）ううっ…
（兵士２）ぐぅ…
They're alive?
（セルゲイ）生きている…
What's happening?
何が起こっている？
ハイランド軍の兵までも…
Even the Hyland soldiers...
至急 救護班を向かわせろ 急げ！
Bring the medics immediately!
Yes, sir!
（セルゲイ）世界はどこへ
向かおうとしているのか…
Where is this world heading?
でいっ！
You wish to defeat my master?
我が主を倒したいのであろう？
主の奴婢(ぬひ)を倒せないようでは
到底無理ぞ
Then you must first defeat his servants.
Feel the power of human malevolence.
人間の持つ穢れの力を感じるがよい
やつらの業 果てはないぞ
Their sins are limitless.
サイモン 行くぞ
Symonne, let's go.
よろしいのですか？
Are you sure?
（ヘルダルフ）生き残れよ 導師
Survive, Shepherd.
貴様が人間どもの希望となって
それを わしがたたきのめす
You will become humanity's beacon of hope, and then I will crush you.
I can think no greater despair than for the people to see their symbol of hope fail.
この世に生きる者にとって
これ以上の絶望もあるまい
スレイばかりに頼っていられない
I can't let Sorey do all the work!
導師に比べれば 僕らが
できることは限られているけど
We seraphim can't do everything the Shepherd can.
I can at least scatter them.
散らすことならできるわ
Edna!
エドナ
Lailah...
（スレイ）ライラ！
さあ 行きますわよ
Let's go.
Where are you going?
（デゼル）どこへ行くつもりだ？
何よ またあんた？
Not you again!
（デゼル）もっと南だ
Further south.
You want to find that Sorey guy, right?
（デゼル）スレイってやつの
ところへ行きたいんだろ？
I said...
だから…
Just shut up and follow my directions.
なら黙って
俺の言うとおりに操縦しな
どっち？
Which way?
Go south, along that cliff on the far end.
このまま南に向かって
奥の崖沿いに行け
Got it!
（ロゼ）了解！
しっかし… なんて穢れだ
Seriously...
What is this malevolence?
It's as if all of the malevolence in the world is gathering there.
世界中の穢れが
そのエリアに集中してるみたいだぜ
This is really bad.
けったくそ悪い
（ロゼ）まったく
No kidding.
ハァ ハァ ハァ ハァ…
It looks like it's over.
どうやら 終わったようだね
だな
Yeah.
（ロゼ）はっ… スレイ！
Sorey!
ふんっ！
でやっ
（デゼル）こんなところで
くたばんないでくれよ
You can't die here, kid.
お前さんには まだ
やってもらいたいことがあるんだ
There's still something I want you to do.
スレイ…
Sorey!
（アリーシャ）思い出してた
I was thinking back...
スレイを導師と間違った
最初に出会った時のこと
To the time we first met when I thought you were the Shepherd.
スレイが導師にふさわしいと言って
別れた時のこと
To when we parted ways, I told you that you'd make a great Shepherd.
スレイが導師になった
聖剣祭の時のこと
To the Sacred Blade Festival where you became the Shepherd.
思い出してた
A lot happened.
私は今も鮮明に覚えている
I remember it all so vividly.
人間と天族が 仲よく一緒に
暮らすことが夢だと言った―
You said your dream was for humans and seraphim to live together in peace.
あの時のこと
I will never forget
改めて思う
those words.
伝承にある導師 それはきっと―
I'm sure, now more than ever, that the Shepherd of legend...
スレイ 君のような人だと思う
was someone like you, Sorey.
スレイでよかった
I'm glad it was you.
ありがとう
Thank you.
（スレイ）俺こそ
アリーシャがいてくれてよかった
I'm glad that you were here too, Alisha.
最初に出会った人間が
アリーシャだったから―
I'm glad that the first human I ever met was you.
俺は夢を信じることが
できたのかもしれない
Maybe that's why I was able to believe in my dream.
私はレディレイクに戻ろうと思う
I plan to return to Ladylake.
最前線での戦いは大事だ
The fighting in the front lines is important.
しかし 私の役目は―
But...
My role is to fight in the world of politics to prevent wars.
戦争が起こらないように
政治の世界で戦うこと
これ以上
ムダな血が流れないように
To prevent more bloodshed.
（スレイ）アリーシャ
俺と従士(じゅうし)の契りを交わそう
Alisha, I want you to become my Squire.
従士…
Squire?
（スレイ）
アリーシャの力に なりたいんだ
I want to help you.
しかし スレイの負担に
なるのではないか？
But won't that be a burden on you?
俺が強くなればいい
I just need to become stronger.
スレイ…
Sorey...
分かった 私からもお願いする
All right, I'd like that.
私を君の従士にしてほしい
Please make me your squire.
（スレイ）いつだって一緒だ
We'll always be together.
ライラ 頼む
Lailah, will you?
（ライラ）はい
Yes.
（ライラ）
スレイさん 私の詠唱に続いて―
Sorey...
After my incantations, give Alisha a true name in the ancient tongue.
アリーシャさんに 古代語の真名を
与えてあげてください
A new bud forms on the holy branch.
我が宿りし聖なる枝に
新たなる芽 いずる
花は実に 実は種に
Its flowers bring fruit.
Its fruit begets seeds.
The circle of destiny turns once more.
巡りし宿縁をここに寿(ことほ)がん
今 導師の意になる命を与え
連理の証しとせん
Give life unto the will of the Shepherd, and let it be proof of their bond.
覚えよ 従士たる 汝(なんじ)の真名は…
Thy true name as Squire shall be...
マオクス＝アメッカ
Melphis Amekia.
It means "Alisha the Smiling."
“笑顔のアリーシャ”っていう
意味だよ
（アリーシャ）ありがとう スレイ
Thank you, Sorey.
（スレイ）いつか また
Let's meet again someday.
Yes, we shall meet again.
また会おう
（ロゼ）なになに～？
見つめ合っちゃったりしちゃって～
Hey, how come you're gazing into each other's eyes?
Let me join in?
私も仲間に入れてよ
あ… ロゼ
H-Hey, Rose!
This is goodbye for us too, so why does Sorey get special treatment?
（ロゼ）私とも お別れでしょ
何でスレイだけ？
Oh... Fine. Here.
もう… じゃあ はい
（ロゼ）うっわ 適当すぎ！
Aw, so proper!
（アリーシャ）えっ… あっ
（ロゼ）アッハハ…
Those three sure are getting along.
仲がいいわね
これが青春ってやつですわ
I believe this is what's called puberty.
Yeah, right.
違うだろ
Hey, shake my hand too, Sorey!
（ロゼ）ほら スレイも握手！
Sorey!
（ミクリオ）スレイ！
Shepherd!
（ランドン）導師よ
How dare you take my military exploits away from me?!
このランドンの武功を
邪魔立てする気だろう
I won't let you do this!
許さぬぞ！
Landon?! Why are you...
ランドン！？ その姿は…
Once I bring your head to Bartlow, he will know who is more important to this nation!
バルトロ閣下も
貴様の首を見れば―
私と どちらが国にとって必要か
分かるというもの
This is...
これは…
これが憑魔化した姿ですわ
This is his transformation into a hellion.
Hellion...
憑魔…
Sorey, he's the one who attacked the princess!
（ロゼ）スレイ こいつだよ
姫様をやったやつ！
こいつがアリーシャを！？
He hurt Alisha?!
You idealistic fool of a princess!
（ランドン）
お前のような世間知らずの姫は―
The nation has no need of you either!
国も必要とはせん！
導師と一緒に―
I'll finish you and the Shepherd right now!
今 始末してやる！
（スレイ）こんなやつが―
This idiot threatened Alisha?
アリーシャの命を…
No, Sorey! Don't give in to anger!
ダメですわ スレイさん
怒りに身を任せては！
You bastards...
（スレイ）こんなやつが…
Because there are guys like you...
お前みたいなやつがいるから―
この世界は！
This world is...
（ライラ）スレイさん ダメ！
No, Sorey!
スレイさん！
Sorey...
（スレイ）
お前みたいなやつがいるから…
Because of guys like you...
やめるんだ スレイ！
Stop, Sorey!
穢れに取り込まれるわよ
He'll get taken over by malevolence.
うっ くうっ…
うりゃあああっ
Sorey...
スレイさん！
上出来だわ
Well done.
スレイ…
Sorey...
（アリーシャ）この者は
私がレディレイクへ連れて帰る
I'll take him back to Ladylake.
He'll have a proper and fair trial.
正式な裁判にかけ
司法にその罪を裁いてもらう
それでいいな
Is that acceptable?
（ミクリオ）スレイ
Sorey...
You handled yourself well.
よく耐えたね
I'm glad.
よかった
（ロゼ）導師スレイ
Shepherd Sorey...
何だよ 急に
What now?
Remember that one favor you owe me?
いつかの貸しのこと覚えてる？
She's definitely up to no good.
きっと ろくでもないこと
考えているぞ
同感ね
I totally agree.
Well, I'm here to collect.
頼み事があるんだけど
I knew it.
やっぱり
頼み事？
What do you want?
（ロゼ）大丈夫よ
Don't worry. I'm not gonna force you to take sides in a war or something.
別に戦争で どっちにつけって
いうような話じゃないから
You should refuse.
断ったほうがいい
I totally agree.
同感ね
I have some business in Rolance.
これからローランスで
取り引きがあるんだけど―
一緒に来てくれないかな
Will you come with me?
He's a hard one to negotiate with.
交渉が ちょっと
やっかいな やつなんだよね
で 導師が一緒なら―
Having the Shepherd with me might help with negotiations.
交渉もうまくいくんじゃないかなあ
と思って
That's all?
それだけ？
（ロゼ）それだけよ
That's all.
みんな どう？
What do you all think?
Well, that sounds okay.
それなら まあ…
一応 ローランスには
行く予定だったわけだし
We were planning to go to Rolance anyway.
It's your decision, Sorey.
スレイさんに お任せしますわ
Okay, we'll go to Rolance with you, Rose.
（スレイ）分かった
ロゼと一緒にローランスへ行くよ
All right! Now we're even.
よおし！ これで貸し借りなしね
ところで あいつは
どこかにいるの？
By the way, is that guy around here?
What guy?
あいつって？
あいつは あいつよ
You know, that guy.
Oh, he's over there.
あいつなら あそこに
Are you serious?
（ロゼ）マジ！？
（デゼル）フン
Sheesh!
He seems like quite the character.
あいつ 意外と
おちゃめなやつかもしれないな
This could be fun.
楽しくなりそうですわ
バカね
Idiots.
さあ 行こう！
Okay, let's go!